(light techno music)
- [Instructor] Now we have the
enemies following the
player around the scene,
and what we want to do is
introduce a new mechanic into this game,
and so we'll actually create a power-up
to give the player some
temporary superpowers.
So if we go down to our Project window,
in our Assets folder,
there is a Course Library
where we have Pickups,
and we can choose any kind of
Pickup that we want to use.
I think I'm gonna use this gem
just because it's large so
it's a bit easier to see.
So you can kinda see it there.
We're going to rename
the gem to be Powerup,
and then we're gonna just
change its scale and position
so that way we can play around with it.
Put it up there.
I'll zero this, just
make these round numbers.
Now, our Powerup is a bit small
and it's a little hard to see,
so we're actually going to focus on it
and make it a bit larger.
So let's see what happens if we do 1.5,
0.5, and 1.5.
I'll just make it all round, too.
Cool.
Now it's very easy to see within our game.
Now we're going to go to our Add Component
in our Powerup Inspector.
We're going to add a Box Collider
so that we can actually collide with this.
It looks pretty good.
Think it fits around nicely.
Yeah, cool, that's fine.
And then we're just going to make sure
that we check the Is Trigger box
so then that way we can
actually collide with it
with our player
and then have it do something
when we hit the actual gem.
Now we can add a tag to our Powerup
so that way it's easier to find,
and we'll tag it as Powerup
and then just make sure in the Inspector,
on your Powerup, to just apply that tag,
and then we're going to take our Powerup
and we're just going to drag
and drop it into our Prefabs folder,
and we're going to make
an original Prefab,
and then there you go.
And now we have our
Powerup and our Prefabs,
and you can see it here.
So what you're gonna do
is you're gonna go into
your Assets folder,
go into the Pickups
under the Course Library,
select one on your own, drag
and drop it into the Hierarchy,
and then you can just position it
so that it's a little
bit better positioned.
And then you're going
to rename it Powerup,
make sure to add a Box Collider,
change the scale so
that it's a bit larger,
and then apply a tag for
it to be called Powerup.
Now it's your turn.
(light techno music)